The radiance of the night shines through my window
but the path to immortality is long.
The Eight Views and Nine-Bend Streams are desolate.
Living beings question the miseries of the world over a jar of wine.
Forget about Nirvana and rebirth,
I will break through the waves with my own flesh and blood.
The heavens are vast, so what if I was born mediocre ?
I stare at the Dao in my moments of madness
as the storm rages just below.
I've been thinking about life and death in my dreams.
I've unsheathed my sword to ask the immortals
why the world is a-changing.
Heaven and earth reveals its poignant truths.
Swallow the Four Seas and the Eight Wastelands,
experience all the vicissitudes of life in an instant.
I will defy the light in the sky
to continue to write a new chapter for all things in the three realms of existence.
Just a thought separates mortal from immortal.
Transform your insignificant body into light.
The hardships of the journey
will temper this young man's heart.
If I become a Renegade Immortal, will I hesitate to fight the heavens ?
Renegade Immortal
Subtitles by Bonobosubs
https://discord.gg/Ceckd4pdVA
Main Road
Country of Zhao
Liu San
Wei Wu Mercenary Agency
We made it through safely
thanks to you, Chief.
Yang Sen
Wei Wu Mercenary Agency
Chief,
we are escorting a valuable shipment this time.
We should be getting a 10% cut, right ?
Du Feng
Wei Wu Mercenary Agency
The Boss has always been fair
as long as we complete the delivery.
We’re only 4 days away from Tianshui City now.
Stay focused !
Got it !
Yang Sen, go check it out.
Okay.
Young man, you’ve got guts.
I’m Yang Sen from the Wei Wu Mercenary Agency.
Why are you walking the Main Road alone ?
Do you need help ?
My name is Wang Lin,
I'm a woodcarver.
I’m heading to Tianshui City to make a living
but I’m lost.
Could you tell me how to get to Tianshui City ?
What a coincidence, we’re also going to Tianshui City.
You can come with us.
Thank you very much.
Senior,
I finished inscribing this jade tablet as you taught me.
Good. After refining it,
this jade talisman has become a Core Formation artifact.
A Core Formation artifact ?
Yes, a Core Formation artifact,
an artifact with the power of a Core Formation cultivator.
That Sun Dazhu was such a fool,
he had good artifacts but didn't know how to refine them.
If not for my knowledge,
these artifacts would have been wasted.
Senior,
I'm already at the peak of Qi Condensation.
If I go to Tianshui City
and find some wood element materials
to upgrade the Heaven Defying Bead,
will I be able to reach Foundation Establishment ?
Not yet.
How long will it take ?
How long ?
You blockhead !
If you think this method is too slow,
then listen to me
and steal a Foundation.
Senior...
I don't think I can capture a Foundation Establishment cultivator alive.
And even if I did,
that person would die without a doubt.
Foundation Stealing
is a bit too cruel for me.
It's the law of the jungle,
harming others for your own benefit is natural !
With your mindset,
you’ll suffer sooner or later.
Brother Wang arrived at the right time.
Today is the day Mister Li is reading our fortunes.
Mister Li
Wei Wu Mercenary Agency
You’re really lucky,
Mister Li is a living Immortal.
Fine,
I’ll read your fortunes today.
Thank you, sir.
Dark clouds loom over you,
you will be part of a bloodshed.
This calamity is imminent,
but if you can survive it
you’ll have a romantic encounter within 3 months.
As a mercenary, I'm always in danger.
Being in bloodsheds
is inevitable.
Weird...
Why are you also part of a bloodshed ?
Old Liu, you too have bloodshed in your fortune !
This...
Everyone here has signs of a bloodshed.
This doesn’t look good !
You...
Senior...
Mister, does he also have a bloodshed in his fortune ?
It has nothing to do with this young man
but my fortune-telling skills might be lacking...
I can’t see through him.
This Junior's fortune-telling is interesting.
I sent him memories of me killing people.
Who is here !?
Show your face at once !
Mister Liu San,
hand over the ginseng
and we won't hurt anyone !
Song Xing
Mortal
Song Xing, you are pathetic.
Let’s see who won’t leave alive !
Immortal... an Immortal spell !
Hand over the ginseng,
or you will die.
Zhang Hu ?
Old Liu, just hand it over.
How can mortals like us resist an Immortal ?
The boss won’t blame us.
Bold of you !
You...
You’re actually an Immortal !
You're meeting an old friend
yet you won’t you come out and greet me ?
Greetings, Boss !
Who are you ?
Hand over the ginseng if you know what’s good for you.
Otherwise,
don’t blame me for being ruthless.
Something's wrong...
My bad,
I mistook you for someone else.
You’re a smart one.
Now get lost !
Greetings, Immortal !
Bai Zhan
Rogue cultivator
15th layer of Qi Condensation
Master.
Immortal, please spare us.
He's at the peak of Qi Condensation.
The same level as you.
Perfect,
Little Lin,
it's a good opportunity to try out your new artifacts.
Zhang Hu,
why don't you greet
this old friend of yours.
Master,
disciple doesn’t know this person.
Good.
8th layer of Qi Condensation...
If I can drink his blood
it will surely boost my cultivation.
I’ll help you, Master.
Master...
Did you think
I didn't see that speed talisman !?
Master !
This person is a friend of mine.
Please...
please spare him !
So you were trying to help him escape ?
You overestimate yourself.
This guy
probably used a control poison on Zhang Hu.
You’re not at the 8th layer !
Even if you're Foundation Establishment,
you won’t escape this flying sword !
Such a fast sword !
This flying sword is strange.
Little Lin, be careful !
This... this is a Core Formation artifact !
I am Old Man Ji Mo's disciple !
This kind of life or death battle
is perfect to temper you.
Only then
can you see the true nature of the cultivation world.
He’s dead...
Was it because of him
that you didn't acknowledge me earlier ?
He’s really dead !
Wang Lin,
this isn’t the place to talk.
We can catch up
after we dispose of them.
Dead persons won't talk !
Bai Zhan is Old Man Ji Mo's disciple,
he'll investigate this matter !
If he does,
we won't be able to escape death !
Exalted Immortals,
we swear we won’t say a word.
You won't ?
But if someone extracts your soul and refines it,
they will know everything.
I erased their memories of tonight.
Let’s go.
It’s been many years
since we parted at Heng Yue Sect.
After you left the Heng Yue Sect,
I had no one else to drink with.
Same here...
I need to find a safe place
to refine this flying sword into my artifact.
If we need to fight,
it will increase our chances.
Perfect.
I was planning to lay low in the nearby Teng Family City.
Let’s go together.
Otherwise, who knows when we’ll meet again ?
Teng Family City ?
The Teng Family is a cultivation family
with a Nascent Soul Ancestor.
No one in Zhao dares to provoke them.
Fighting is forbidden inside the city.
Outsiders can enter by paying a few spirit stones
and settle here.
Even Old Man Ji Mo
wouldn't dare to cause a ruckus here.
Foundation Establishment...
Stay away,
he's from the Corpse Sect.
The Corpse Sect ?
The Corpse Sect is present everywhere.
Every cultivation country,
has one branch of it.
Come in.
The coffin contains a Corpse Puppet,
a puppet refined from a corpse.
It's the secret technique of their sect.
The higher the disciple’s cultivation,
the stronger the Corpse Puppet.
Please come in.
What brings you here this time ?
Stay away from them in the future,
the Corpse Sect is evil.
Fellow cultivator, come take a look !
Inn
Teng Family City
It's trying to escape !?
Artifacts with a spirit
really are different.
Senior,
is there a way for me to refine it quickly ?
I have a method
but you won't dare to use it.
Why ?
It’s called Blood Refining.
You need to use your Soul Blood to refine it.
The upside is that the sword will be yours instantly.
The downside however...
is that if the sword is damaged, you also will be.
The backlash will be far worse than with regular methods.
I’ll do it.
Please teach me, Senior.
Oh ?
You’re quite ruthless on yourself.
If you used this ruthlessness on others,
you'd already be Foundation Establishment.
Wang Lin,
are you sure you won’t come with me to sell the ginseng ?
I’m busy,
go without me.
Residence of the Ancestor
Teng Family City
This is a small token of my respect.
I hope Ancestor Teng will help me.
Old Man Ji Mo
Rogue cultivator
Early stage Core Formation
That's good stuff.
But I am the one who forbade fighting inside the city.
This puts me in a difficult position.
But...
this...
Teng Huayuan
Teng Family Ancestor
Early stage Nascent Soul
Teng Li
Young Master of The Teng Family
Late stage Foundation Establishment
Forgive me.
This is my grandson, Teng Li.
Li'er pays respects to Grandfather.
Well done.
I present to you Old Man Ji Mo,
he's here today to ask for our help.
This Nascent Soul artifact
isn't meant for a Foundation Establishment...
What are you implying ?
That I, Teng Li, am unworthy of this Nascent Soul artifact ?
Hmph !
Then let me show you.
Look, what’s that ?
The clouds have been torn open !
Young Master, please avenge my disciple.
The Soul Blood is the most important part of a cultivator's soul. Destroying someone's Soul Blood instantly collapses that person's soul. Unless it is willingly given to someone, cultivators will always keep it safely inside their soul. This is why using it in blood refining is dangerous and has consequences if the blood refined artifact is damaged or destroyed.
Artifacts can house a spirit, making them sentient. In the case of a sword, the spirit will be referred to as a Sword Spirit. That's the case of Wang Lin's new sword.
A rogue cultivator is a cultivator without a sect (Wang Lin is a rogue since he lost his sect).
Spirit stones are the money used by cultivators. They're basically a crystalized form of spiritual energy that is naturally formed in areas dense in spiritual energy known as Spirit Veins. The energy from a spirit stone can thus be absorbed to heal, to cultivate, to power a formation, etc... There are grades of spirit stones depending on the density of spiritual energy inside it.
'er at the end of a name is the equivalent of an affective nickname. Here Teng Li refers to himself as "Li'er" when talking to Teng Huayuan because his grandfather calls him "Li'er".
I've been walking this path for endless years
just to catch a glimpse of your silhouette.
Is it the compass of fate
that wrote this outcome for us ?
The heavens want to erase your existence,
that's the obsession guiding me.
Is this the path to uncover
truths from falsehoods ?
In a world of murk and shadow,
only the flame of truth can light the way.
Look at them all,
being carried by the waves.
being drowned.
I don't want to believe in whoever decides fate,
I will let the world refine my soul.
So what if I become an Immortal and defy the heavens ?
I will fight.
I'll break through the abyss of despair
to finally learn who I really am.
My body is stained by the bloody color of slaughter,
I embrace this obsession.
I won't glance back at the wasteland I left behind.
Even if this suffering shatters my soul
and I'm reborn countless times in hell,
I'll still fight.
It's hard to avoid loneliness
when you are above everyone else.
Can a moth that has witnessed the flames of a Suzaku
be afraid of a firefly ?